# David M. Messina, CSPO

Newfield, NJ 08344 - 856.952.4572 - DMessina79@gmail.com - www.linkedin.com/in/dave-messina

# Information Technology Management Business Solutions Architecture – Systems & Network Administration

Technical Support & Troubleshooting
Project Management & Agile Methodologies
Process Design & Improvement
Product Development & Marketing
Vendor Partnerships
Data Analysis
Staff Hiring, Training, & Leadership

Over 15 years of IT experience and a record of excellent leadership and high client satisfaction.

Self-motivated to find opportunities to lower costs, refine processes, and build collaborative relationships.

Dedicated and efficient problem solver and multitasker.

Superb communication skills with senior leadership, colleagues, vendors, and customers.

## CAREER ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Increased targeted sales opportunities for Linode by 35% by devising and executing product pipeline process from lead generation to delivery.
- Created overall infrastructure and daily workflow procedures for every department at Sports Vault, contributing to \$4M growth in three years.
- Surpassed quotas for systems installation as Deployment Team Lead for Navy/Marine Corps Intranet (NMCI) project at Philadelphia Naval Base.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LINODE - Philadelphia, PA

2013-2018

Product Manager & System Administrator, 2015-2018

Customer Support Manager, 2013-2015

Customer Support Specialist, 2013-2013

Presided over professional services division, which conducted cloud infrastructure design, application migration, and Linux system administration services for wide-ranging companies. Marketed products. Generated operational reports to keep leaders informed.

- Project Management: Directed more than 500 projects and attained 90% satisfaction rate using Scrum methodologies.
- **Team Leadership:** Trained and coached team of four Solutions Consultants, educating them on requirements gathering and contract organization.
- Data Analysis: Took initiative to employ market research to enhance product strategy.
- Client Satisfaction: Promoted from Customer Support Specialist to Manager after receiving customer service excellence award.

#### SPORTS VAULT -- Exton. PA

2005-2013

#### IT Manager & System Administrator

Oversaw all activities in IT department, including planning, budgeting, and purchasing. Supervised store's local area networks (LANs), office datacenter, and Windows Server environment using Active Directory. Upheld end user systems for 40 home office employees and over 50 stores, performing installation and troubleshooting. Constructed and launched website with Magento e-commerce platform.

 Product Development: Expanded online catalogue from 3K products to over 20K products by establishing partnerships with vendors.

# David M. Messina, CSPO

Page 2 • Career Progression (Cont.)

• Cost Containment: Together with Multidev Technologies, integrated a retail management solution called ChainDrive that reduced costs by 70% and increased operational efficiency.

#### ELECTRONICS BOUTIQUE OF AMERICA — West Chester, PA

2004-2005

#### PC Hardware Technician

Delivered desktop support for over 200 laptops. Addressed staff members' XP functionality questions and software problems. Arranged audiovisual equipment for seminars, workshops, and executive meetings.

Process Improvement: Expedited repair process by solidifying automation system for imaging laptops and desktops.

#### PHILADELPHIA NAVAL BASE, NMCI PROJECT — Philadelphia, PA

2003-2004

#### **Development Team Lead & Configuration Technician**

Set up over 2.5K Dell workstations and laptops. Recorded system outages and other technical issues in end-of-shift reports.

Prior experience as Computer Support Specialist & Network Technician at Rowan University Library.

# **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES**

Operating Systems: Unix (Solaris, FreeBSD), Linux (CentOS, Debian, Ubuntu), Windows Server 2008/2016,

Windows 7/10, Mac OS X

Software: Apache, MySQL, Nginx, HAProxy, Galera, GlusterFS, Percona Tools, KVM, Docker, Zapier,

Postman, Jira, Basecamp, Harvest, Confluence, HubSpot, Slack

Hardware: Cisco Pix/ASA Firewalls and Catalyst Switches, Dell PowerEdge Servers and PowerConnect

Switches, Juniper SRX (JunOS)

Networking: TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP, OSI Model, VPN, Firewall Management

# **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

GLOUCESTER COUNTY INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Sewell, NJ Coursework in Computer Information Systems & Information Technology

#### Certifications

LPIC-1 Certification (In Progress)
Certified Scrum Product Owner (2017)

#### **Professional Development**

Web Development 101 Course in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Ruby (Expected Completion in July 2018)